Now, we're going to go ahead and take a look at our G7 shape.
Again, reviewing from our scale degree segment, our G7 is going to consist of our 1, G, the scale degree of 3 which is our B, 5 which is our D and now we're going to add our flat 7 in there which--if we just take our natural 7 which would be an F sharp, drop it down, it becomes an F natural.
Reviewing our shape, it's pretty similar to our G major.
We've got our G, our B, our 1 and our 3, 5 D, G again.
Now, instead of playing the D and G up here, I actually dropped this down to a B which is another note of our chord.
It's okay to do that as long as we're playing notes of the chord.
And it makes it a little bit easier to get to this F which is our flat 7.
Okay, I'm looking over here at the scale degrees--1, 3, 5, 1, 3, flat 7; that's going to be our highest note there.
And what we're going to do is play it a little bit differently than we play our G major shape.
Instead of using 2 and 1 and our left hand to play that G and the B, we're actually going to use 3 and 2.
What that's going to do is allow us to take our index finger and bring it down to hit that F. That's our F there.
When we hit it all together, it makes it a little bit easier to play it that way using this shape.
That's the G7.